The frequency spectrum of the ball lightning now matches the human body precisely.
现在球闪的频谱已经和人体精准匹配
This is a masterpiece specially created for you.
这是专门为您完成的杰作
The signal near the high-altitude station disappeared instantly.
高空站附近的信号瞬间消失了
Above.
上面
It's like suddenly adding a transparent cover.
像突然多了个透明的罩子
The ball lightning pierced the boundaries between macro and micro,
球状闪电击穿了宏观和微观的界限
and the quantum body it formed.
它所形成的量子体
Like mold,
像一朵霉菌
it infected the macro world we are in.
感染了我们所在的宏观世界
Once it begins to expand,
一旦它开始扩张
The entire space will produce mutations that we do not understand
整个空间都会产生我们不了解
and cannot control.
更没办法控制的异变
I pressed it.
我按了
I listened to you.
听你的
Alert.
警报
The ball lightning recovery program is interrupted.
球状闪电回收程序中断
Please check immediately.
请立即检修
Alert.
警报
The ball lightning recovery program is interrupted.
球状闪电回收程序中断
Please check immediately.
请立即检修
As the first person to break a wallfacer,
作为第一个破壁的人
you are worthy of admiration.
你值得敬佩
Von Neumann.
冯・诺伊曼
Our lord
主
will be with you forever.
将与你永在
He faced only
他面对的只是一个
a poor strategist.
拙劣的战略家
An unqualified wallfacer.
一个不合格的面壁者
You envy him.
你妒忌他
Rey Diaz's hibernation application
雷迪亚兹的冬眠申请
has been approved.
已经通过了
The same goes for Hines.
希恩斯也一样
It seems that in a regular life
看来正常尺度的一生里
we can complete our mission.
我们就可以完成使命了
But do you want to know
但你不想知道
What is happening on
天梯
the Ladder now?
现在到底发生了什么吗
Tyler has been broken,
泰勒是被破壁了
but Luo Ji is still there.
但罗辑还在上面
I only know
我只知道
what the lord needs me to know.
主需要我知道的
Don't forget
别忘了
Luo Ji confronts the Lord directly
罗辑直接与主对决
and
而且
whether it is ETO
不论对ETO
or ordinary humans
还是普通人类
the lord's blockade of the sub-atomic
主对微观的封锁
is complete.
都是彻底的
Just checked one and panicked.
刚检查了一 急
The door that can directly leave the cabin is broken
能直接出舱的门坏了
and this window is made of aerospace glass
这窗户又是航天玻璃
which didn't even break from high-speed debris.
高速碎片都没击穿
We definitely can't smash it open,
我们肯定砸不开
And even if we go out,
而且就算出去了
how to return to the ground is also a problem.
怎么回地面也是问题
Fortunately, there are still supplies left.
好在物资还有剩
Do you think
你觉得
the PDC knows we're still alive?
PDC知道我们还活着吗
Hard to say.
不好说
I've always wanted to ask.
我一直想问
Do you really have the ability to defeat aliens?
你真的有战胜外星人的本领吗
Well
好吧
Look here.
看这里
I just need to snap my fingers
我只要打个响指
and the solar system
太阳系
will disappear.
就会消失
You really believe that?
还真信
I'm kidding you.
骗你的
There are no superheroes in this world.
这世界上没有超人
Wallfacers.
可面壁者
Aren't they?
不就是吗
If only that were true.
要是就好了
Do I look like a superhero now?
你看我现在像超人吗
What's going on? Why hasn't the Chairman arrived yet?
怎么回事啊萨伊主席怎么还没到
The Ladder is the core of human near-earth defense works.
天梯可是人类近地防御工事的核心
What's happening now?
现在什么情况
It is said that only one cabin has been destroyed.
听说只撞毁了一个舱道
Not sure.
不清楚
The flight control center is not releasing any information.
飞控中心不放消息
It must be related to the wallbreaker.
肯定和破壁有关
What about the rescue plan?
救援方案呢
Why isn't she bringing it to a vote?
她怎么不拿给我们投票
It is said that the wallfacer Luo Ji is up there.
听说面壁者罗辑在上面
Really?
真的
That's troublesome.
那麻烦了
Contact Ronan.
跟罗南联系
Ask how long the chairman will take.
问主席还要多久
No need.
不用
I'll attend the meeting on behalf of the chairman.
我代萨伊主席参会
No one can replace her.
没人能代替她
That's right.
没错
So the chairman must command the rescue effort with all her might.
所以主席必须全力指挥救援
For other matters
其他事情
she has authorized me.
她授权给我了
The only way is to give up the Ladder.
唯一的办法是放弃天梯
Why?
为什么
Images from the low-altitude station show that there
低空站传来的图片显示
are now two symmetrical quantum bodies near the high-altitude station.
高空站现在有两个对称量子体
It should be what Dr. Ding said.
应该就是丁博士说的
The symmetrical energy range formed
以宏原子核为中心
with the macro atomic nucleus as the center.
形成的对称能量范围
The human understanding of the sub-atomic is too limited.
但人类对微观的了解太有限了
The only thing we can do is
唯一能做的可能就是
to keep it away from us.
可以让它远离我们
You see.
您看
The top weight station is also a nuclear power plant.
顶部的配重站也是核电站
As long as the maximum magnetic force is turned on,
只要开启最大磁力
The quantum body will be attracted
量子体就会被吸引
and as it floats towards the Yellow River Station..
随着黄河站飘向深空
It will be attracted.
被吸引
Are you sure?
你确定
Yes.
对
I can't say anything else,
别的不敢说
but I found that
但我发现
the properties of the macro electron
即使球闪变成了量子体
have been preserved
宏电子的属性还是保留了下来
so these original properties
所以这些原始属性
can be fully utilized
完全可以被我们利用
such as
比如
magnetic confinement.
磁力约束
Have you verified it?
您验证了
theoretically, right?
理论上是吧
In Dr. Elena's final message.
我在埃琳娜博士最后的信息里
I found the energy level data of the ball lightning.
找到了球闪的能级数据
After inputting it into the calculated quantum body model
输入推算的量子体模型后
it unexpectedly worked.
竟然走通了
What does this mean?
这说明什么
DNA.
DNA
Like human DNA
像人类的DNA一样
some things are unchangeable.
有些东西是不会变的
Ball lightning can be confined by a magnetic field
球状闪电能被磁场约束
and the quantum body should be able to as well.
量子体应该也可以
This means
这就意味着
that starting the nuclear power plant at the top of the ladder
启动了天梯顶部的核电站
is like creating a predictable
就相当于我们创造了一个可预期的
path for the quantum body.
量子体的移动路线
Eventually, the Yellow River Station will split in two
最后黄河站会一分为二
and the detached part
脱离的部分
will be carried into deep space with the quantum body.
会和量子体一起被带向深空
Also, the fluctuations of the macro gravity particles are not continuous.
而且宏引力子的涨落不是持续的
Once the gravity towards humans weakens
一旦对人的引力减弱
the survivors have a good chance of being rescued.
幸存者有很大概率等到我们救援
Can the auxiliary nuclear power plant handle the power?
副核电站的功率能行吗
The risk assessment table data is not good.
风险评估表数据不太好啊
It's about right.
差不多
All departments have done their best
各部门都尽力了
and the verification data has been submitted.
核验数据已经提交了
This is all we can do now.
现在只能这样了
But we cannot get through the fiber optic cable to go up
但我们往上的光纤走不通
and all wireless signals are lost.
无线信号又全部失联
The only control panel that can send instructions to the Yellow River Station
唯一能给黄河站发指令的操作台
is the one in the high-altitude station.
只剩下高空站的了
Our spacecraft cannot enter
我们的飞船又进不去
and we cannot contact the survivors.
幸存者又联系不上
We are just waiting to die.
还不是等死
This is
这事儿
so bizarre.
够邪乎
We need to come up with a solution.
得出邪招
Don't keep us in suspense.
别卖关子
Speak up.
快说
I have a way
找人这事
to find someone.
我有法子
Dr. Ding
丁博士
Can you see what is up there?
咱能看得见上面
Then it must not be completely blocked by the light.
那它肯定遮不住光吧
Strictly speaking,
严格来说
only a portion of visible light
是所有电磁波里
can penetrate all electromagnetic waves.
只有部分可见光能穿过
Alright.
得嗡
Do you have something that can emit light.
能发光的东西你这有吧
Like a long-range reflective object?
照巨远的那种
Does this count?
反光的算吗
Solar panels?
太阳能板
That will work.
那成了
Chairman,
主席
have you heard of a beacon tower?
听说过烽火台吗
Sure, Da Shi,
可以啊大史
but the way to communicate with the quantum body
和量子体内通讯的办法
has really stumped you.
还真被你给蒙着了
The 16th transmission
第16次传递
has selected the No. 5 sail panel array,
选定5号帆板阵列
with a positive azimuth adjustment of 27 arc seconds
方位角正调27角秒
and a negative elevation adjustment of 14 arc seconds.
仰角负调14角秒
The parameters have been entered,
参数已输入
and the target has been focused
对焦目标
on the first ring of the high-altitude station.
高空站一环
Received.
收到
Backup power key for the high-altitude station
高空站备用电源密匙
has been sent for the 46th time.
第46次重复发送
The relative angle of the solar panel has begun to be adjusted
太阳能板相对角度开始微调
to focus on the sunlight.
正聚焦日光
What is the transmission distance?
传递距离是多少
Focal length of 16,000 kilometers,
焦距1.6万公里
with a deviation of less than 50 meters
偏差得50米以内
to ensure that the C-ring road in the first ring can see it.
确保一环C环道能瞧见
There are probably only a few people left breathing among the survivors.
估计就那几个地有喘气的了
No problem.
没问题
Even with slight scattering on the light path,
即使加上光路上的轻微散射
the light intensity is sufficient.
光照强度也足够了
I just don't know how many survivors
就是不知道幸存者里
in there can understand Morse code.
能看懂摩斯电码的有几个
Sometimes
我有时候
I wonder
也在想
if it's hard for you
做了这么久面壁者
to be a wallfacer
你
for so long.
肯定很难吧
Yeah.
是啊
I wish it was easier.
但我想做得容易些
That's how it is.
就是这样
When Michelangelo painted "Genesis"
米开朗基罗画《创世纪》的时候
there was a worker who
有个小工帮他递笔刷
passed him brushes.
递过来接过去
It took over four years,
四年多的时间
but he said it was his most meaningful work
但他说这是最有意义的工作
because he could never paint "Genesis" himself.
因为他自己永远画不出《创世纪》
If he could give a little help to the painter,
如果可以给画画的人出一点力
he would feel valuable too.
好像自己也有了价值
That's how I felt after meeting you.
这就是我遇到你之后的心情
You compared me to Michelangelo.
你把我比成米开朗基罗
Do you know how great he was?
你知道他有多厉害吗
Yes.
知道啊
I studied art history.
我学过美术史
I shouldn't have brought you up here.
我不该带你上来
If we never got stuck here.
如果不是困在这儿
I wouldn't have known how beautiful the Earth is.
我都不知道地球这么漂亮
If this is the last scene we see..
如果这是最后的景色了
It's not bad..
倒也不错
Right?
对吗
Luo Ji?
罗辑
Quick
快
Do you have pen and paper?
有没有纸笔
Give it to me quickly.
快给我
Oh my God
我的天哪
What
这是
is this?
什么
Chairman
主席
can't we try something else?
要不换个别的办法
Give them some time
给他们点时间
wait a bit longer.
再等等
Short, short, long.
短短长是
Emergency power supply system has been activated.
已启动应急供能系统
The high-altitude lighting subsystem has temporarily resumed.
高空一环照明子系统临时恢复
Quick, look!
快看
Is there light?
是不是有亮光了
Pass it down, pass it down.
往下传往下传
Hurry up!
快点
The image is coming through.
图片过来了
There's a light source at the high-altitude station.
高空站位置有光源出现
That's great.
太好了
I guessed it right.
我猜对了
It's Morse code.
是摩斯电码
We are saved.
我们有救了
Someone is looking for us.
有人在找我们
We are safe.
我们没事了
That's great, wonderful.
太棒了太好了
Ding Yi, did something happen?
丁仪怎么了
I'm afraid there's no time to celebrate.
恐怕没时间庆祝了
Not to dampen everyone's spirits.
不是扫大家的兴
The data shows that the expansion of the quantum state
数据显示量子体的扩张之后会加快
will accelerate after a certain point.
距离天梯被完全覆盖
There's only about 8 hours left before the Ladder
大约只剩
completely covered.
8小时
What do you mean?
你的意思是
Does it mean that all the survivors on the Ladder
所有天梯上的幸存者
including those in the low-altitude station
包括现在低空站里的人
will all die?
会全部遇难
Yes.
对
Chairman.
主席
The survival area is about to enter the illuminated area.
幸存区域即将进入光照范围
Quick, Shi Qiang.
快史强
Convey this information to the survivors.
向幸存者传达主要内容
Understood.
明白
Don't you all want to know the complete rescue plan?
各位不是想知道救援的完整方案吗
The survivors should be in the C1 emergency shelter
幸存者位置应该在C1应急避难所
so they can activate the backup power supply.
所以能启动备用电源
But it's too close to the quantum body
但那儿距离量子体太近
they have to move to the outer ring compartment
他们得通过外环的舱段
to the
移动到
No.2 gravity port
2号重力港
and then return to the central axis.
再回到中轴
We used it when we came up
咱们上来时那个
but the No.2 gravity port has been destroyed.
但2号重力港已经炸毁了啊
Even if they have to walk outside the cabin,
那怕是得舱外走一段了
the surroundings are all blocked.
旁边都被封死了
The next operation requires a lot of energy.
接下来的操作需要大量能源
So they need to find the N48 supply station along the central axis.
所以得再沿着中轴找到N48补给站
That's a safer option.
也是个安全点
During the process the quantum body will move upward.
因为量子体上移过程中
Make sure it will not move to this location
确保不会移动到这里
and this position
而且这个位置
is the least damaged.
受损最小
But the outside of the cabin is too dangerous.
但是舱外太危险了
The compartment is broken like this.
舱段破成这个样子
So it's safer to wear a space suit outside the cabin.
还不如舱外服里安全
I have calculated
而且我计算过
that once the quantum body starts to move upward,
量子体一旦开始上移
the N48 supply station will for certain be a safe location.
N48补给站会是一个绝对安全的位置
After they complete the operation
等他们操作完成后
they have to return to this location
得回到这个位置
to wait for our rescue.
才能等到我们的救援
Any precautions?
注意事项呢
The space suit is fully intelligent.
舱外服是全智能的
Everything is done according to the UI operation
一切按UI操作就行
except for one thing.
只有一条
Don't enable the visual enhancement mode.
别启用视觉增强模式
What is it?
什么玩意儿
Can you understand it?
你能看懂吗
I'm a second-level engineer.
我二级工程师
What do you think?
你说呢
It's a function developed during the construction of the ladder
天梯建造时开发的功能
which can reconstruct the environmental data around it.
可以重构周围的环境数据
But ordinary people who have not been trained
但没训练过的普通人
will instead affect their normal vision.
反而会影响他们的正常视野
In any case
总之
let's do our best
尽人事
and leave the rest to fate.
听天命吧
They said that this quantum state thing
他们说这个量子态的玩意儿
will soon cover this place.
很快会覆盖这里
What should we do?
我们该怎么办
Since Engineer Yang
杨工程师
can understands it
既然他看得懂
he should also know Morse code.
应该也会用摩斯电码
Ask him to use flashing light to identify himself.
让他用闪光告知身份
In case of any accidents
万一有意外的话
in the last moments
在最后的时间里
humanity will remember his contributions.
所有人类都会纪念他的付出
Chairman.
主席
What's the matter?
怎么样
What did he say?
他说什么
It's Luo Ji.
罗辑
The wallfacer.
面壁者
It turned out to be him.
竟然是他
What a coincidence.
不会这么巧吧
Now we are sure.
这下有把握了
That's great, Chairman.
太好了主席
Stop the operation.
中止行动
Warning: the ladder's gravity system is about to fail.
警告天梯重力系统即将瘫痪
What happened?
怎么了
I don't know.
不知道
Maybe the central axis has a problem.
可能中轴出问题了
Your notes.
你的笔记
Forget it.
别管了
The direction is changing.
方向在变
Hold on to me.
先抓紧我
Okay.
好
Be careful.
小心
Why are we standing on the wall
为什么我们站在墙上
while everything else is floating?
别的东西却飘着
Is it a gravity broken?
是重力故障吗
No.
不
I'm afraid the quantum body is getting closer.
恐怕是量子体靠近了
Quickly
快
let's go to the operating platform.
上操作台去
We have to contact PDC.
我们得和PDC联络
Chairman
主席
there's no other way.
没别的办法了
I think
我认为
the Chairman is following the Wallfacer Act.
主席是在遵照面壁法案行事
But which article in the act
可是法案中的哪一条
allows us to let the wallfacer take such risks?
允许我们让面壁者去冒险呢
Before he receives assistance
他没有得到协助前
he should wait for PDC's rescue at the safe point.
就应该在安全点等待PDC的救援
Chairman
主席
even if we can find another survivor
就算能再找到一个幸存者
it's too late.
时间也来不及了
Only when the nuclear power plant
只有核电站被启动
is started is there any safety
安全点才有安全可言
and without it
所以没有他
the rescue plan cannot be completed.
救援计划不可能完成
However, the lives of the Wallfacers are threatened.
但令面壁者的生命受到威胁
which is the fault of the PDC.
就是PDC的失职
We cannot bear this responsibility.
我们担不起这个责任
Chairman.
主席
At this point
都这份上了
why not let the spacecraft in again?
要不让飞船再进
Engineer Yang,
杨工程师
Ding Yi,
丁仪
I will be out for a few minutes.
我出去几分钟
You cannot do this now.
这时候您不能
PDC Chairman.
PDC主席
You cannot let the Wallfacers be in danger.
不能让面壁者身处险境
But you can establish a temporary staff headquarters for Luo Ji.
不过各位可以成立罗辑的临时参谋部
I will take responsibility
任何后果
for any consequences.
我萨伊承担
Do you understand?
明白
Quickly
快
is there anything else that hasn't been told to the Wallfacers?
还有什么没告诉面壁者的
Upload it.
往上传
Ding Yi
丁仪
we're ready here.
我们这儿齐活了
Hurry.
你赶紧的
Good.
好
The current situation is more complicated than before.
现在的情况比之前复杂
The quantum body has expanded to a certain extent
量子体已经扩张到一定程度
and the gravitational disturbance it produces is constantly increasing.
产生的引力扰动也在不断加强
In theory, the most reliable way for them to escape
按理说 他们处在量子体内部
using the observer effect is to be inside the quantum body.
用观察者效应逃生是最靠谱的
But Luo Ji cannot establish stable
但罗辑现在没法儿和屏蔽层外
communication outside the shielding layer now.
建立稳定的信息交流
His only escape tool now is the space suit.
他现在唯一的逃生工具就是舱外服
However, relying solely on this
但只靠这个
it is impossible to escape the gravitational range in general.
般情况下没法挣脱引力范围
Then what about in specific circumstances?
那二般情况呢
Speak plainly.
说人话
It's like crashing into a high-speed carousel.
好比撞向一个高速的旋转木马
The Wallfacers must jump into the gravity net first
面壁者得先跳进引力网里
in order to exchange angular momentum
才能在弹性碰撞中
in the elastic collision.
和它交换角动量
I get it.
我知道了
Treat it as a gravity booster
把它当做引力助推器
and gain acceleration while turning.
转向的同时获得加速
Yes.
没错
Similar to the gravity slingshot effect.
类似引力弹弓效应
Do we have to head towards the quantum body?
非要朝量子体的方向吗
Why don't we just go straight out of the cabin?
我们为什么不顺着舱道直接出去
We can't escape the gravity directly.
直接挣脱引力是做不到的
We have to borrow force to be thrown out.
只有借力被甩出去才行
No.
不行
The quantum body is too dangerous.
量子体太危险了
Even running won't be fast enough.
人跑都来不及
How can we jump into it?
怎么能往里跳啊
This is the only way out.
这是没办法的办法
The probability density outside the conscious layer is relatively low.
意识层外的概率密度相对比较低
As long as Luo Ji passes through from there
只要罗辑从那儿穿过去
and if the speed is fast enough
而且速度够快的话
the influence of the quantum body can be minimized to the greatest extent.
就能最大程度避免量子体的影响
Jet flow vector angle 31 degrees.
喷流矢量角31度
Jet flow rate 400 per second.
喷流流量每秒400
I've calculated the parameters for the jump.
照我计算出的参数起跳就行
The parameters for the thrusters are set.
推进器参数设置完成
Should I put it on now?
现在戴吗
Ask them to wear their helmets and use the intercom.
叫他们开着头盔对讲
Luo Ji calls Miss Yan.
罗辑呼叫颜小姐
OVER. (End)
OVER（结束）
Miss Yan receiving.
颜小姐收到
There will be
到时候
electromagnetic interference at that time, won't there?
会有电磁干扰吧
If they gets too close to the quantum body
太靠近量子体的话
this effect will occur.
要的就这效果
There's a noise.
杂音 来
I know, that means it's
不就知道那玩意儿近了吗
working better than any alarm.
比什么警报都管用
There are a lot of tricks.
邪招还不少
The cabin depressurization will be completed soon.
舱内泄压即将完成
Please confirm that the preparations are complete
请确认准备工作完成
and you are ready to leave the cabin.
具备出舱条件
Before departure
出发前
you must use the emergency control panel
一定要用应急控制台
to open all the main doors of the cabin.
打开所有舱道主门
Only in this way
只有这样
can they be given the safest
才能给他们尽量腾出一个
path possible for flight.
能安全飞行的空间
Tell him
告诉他
no matter what subverts common sense
无论看到什么颠覆常识的景象
don't panic
另I『慌
and move quickly.
赶紧离开
You're not as cynical as they say
你不像他们说的那么玩世不恭
you are, and in fact, just the opposite.
而且恰恰相反
You've only met a few people.
你才见过几个人
Really.
真的
Uncle Shi said the same thing.
史叔叔也这么说
Before
以前
It was because I didn't care about anything
是因为我什么都没放心上
and didn't take anything seriously.
不在乎
What about now?
那现在呢
Because..
因为
I care too much.
太在乎了
We
我们
have succeeded.
我们成功了
Almost.
差不多
It should be soon.
应该快了
Grab me.
抓住我
Quickly.
快
Detected spatial positioning anomaly.
检测到空间定位异常
System judges cross-compartmental external operation.
系统判定跨舱舱外作业
Visual enhancement mode has been automatically activated.
已自动启用视觉增强模式
I got you.
抓住你了
Wait for me.
等着我
Attitude stabilization mode has been enabled.
姿态稳定模式已启用
Luo Ji, are you ok?
罗辑你怎么样
Wake up quickly.
快醒醒
The super-heavy overload value has dropped to a safe range.
超重过载值降至安全范围
Luo Ji, wake up quickly.
罗辑快醒醒
Visual enhancement mode has been lifted.
视觉增强模式已解除
Look.
看
They're still alive.
他们还活着
Luo Ji.
罗辑
The quantum body seems to be getting closer.
量子体好像在靠近
You have to come back quickly.
你得赶快回来
I can't just leave it alone.
我不能不管
Otherwise, we'll both die here.
不然咱俩都会死在这
Do you hear me?
听到了吗